# **AMIYA RANJAN** RANASINGH

#### FRONTED DEVELOPER

A Front-End Developer as a trainee in Newton School, developing user-friendly websites and web applications. I have a strong command of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and have experience with responsive design and front-end frameworks such as Bootstrap and Foundation. I am a motivated self-starter with a keen eye for detail and a passion for creating pixel-perfect web experiences.

🔀 amiyaranasingh1998@gmail.com 🗓 +91

+918249804259

At - Kalyanpursahi,Barapalla Po-Nabaghanapur , Dist-Nayagarh, State-Odisha

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/amiya-ranjan-ranasingh-234518176/

## https://github.com/ranasinghamiya

#### **SKILLS**

HTML Core Java Linux
CSS GitHub MSExcel
JavaScript MongoDB MsWord
React Js JQuery Ms Powerpoint
Bootstrap React Hook Vs code

WordPress ReactNative Adobe PhotoShop

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Trainee

#### **NEWTON SCHOOL** Oct 2022 - Present

- Trainee front end developers should have a strong understanding of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- They work with web designers and backend developers to create websites and web applications that are userfriendly, effective, and appealing.
- They should also be able to use various web development tools and frameworks.

#### Executive

## Layam Flexi Solutions Pvt Ltd Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

- Prepare MIS data
- Conducted financial analysis, researched business agreements and negotiated critical contracts.
- Conducted financial analysis to manage risks and benefits.
- Report all customer queries by outlook
- Manage all Data
- Data Analysis of Consumers

## **PROJECTS**

#### Frontend Subscription

#### HTML, CSS

The app is basically divided in 3 boxes each with a distinguishing background color and text.

The table should also have some CSS formatting.

The upper box should have should have a CSS class '.community' and background color of "rgb(255, 253, 253)".

The lower box on right side, should have CSS class '.why-us' and background color of "rgba(85, 145, 142, 0.698)".

The lower box on left side, should have CSS class '.card' and background color of "rgb(15, 67, 66)".

The div containing these boxes should have CSS class '.container' and have border radius of 11 px.

Make sure you have exact text in the 'why us' box .

#### Hamburger Menu

#### **BOOTSTRAP**

Cards' header and body have already been provided. Cards' button should be primary with size large and should occupy 100 percent width. Each card should be separated with a gap of 4. Make the cards section responsive, such that,

- on a desktop, all three cards should be placed within a row, and as the screen size decrease, it should change the layout dynamically
- on a tablet, two cards should be placed in a row and one card should be placed in another row
- on a smartphone, all three cards should have their own row, i. e, three cards will occupy three individual rows.

# Style the Payment Form

# HTML, Project

- Give the form container a padding of 15px, and to make the border rounded from the corner, give it a border radius of 4px. Make the background of the form container of color rgb(242, 242, 242). Make the <h1> tag centrally aligned.
- Select the input fields of type text, email, number, password, and date, textarea and select tag. All these will have the same CSS, that is, the input field should have a 100% width, padding of 12px, and a margin of 5px from the top. The font family should be Verdana, Geneva, Tahoma, sans-serif
- Select the fieldset, and make its background of color rgb(255, 255, 255), add a padding of 15px, and make the border of color rgb(204, 204, 204).
- Select the Submit button, and make its background of color rgb(137, 211, 166), add padding and left margin of 10px and 10% respectively. Remove the border, and add a radius to the border of 4px. Increase the width of the button to 80%. When the mouse is hovering over the button, the cursor should change to a pointer. Again, the font family should the Verdana, Geneva, Tahoma, sans-serif

## **Resturant Webite**

Bootstrap

A responsive Website

Calculator

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Commerce**

Utkal University Bhubaneswar Mar 2015 - May 2018

Intermediate of commerce

Council Of Higher Secondary Education Odisha Mar 2013 - Jun 2015

Matriculation

Board of Secondary Education Odisha, India Mar 2012 - Apr 2013

## **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi Odia